<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IEEE Student Branch Karlsruhe (Ankündigungen)</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>de</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 08:19:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Ankündigung: IEEE SB KA ISIC 2024!</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2024/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-isic-2024/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2024/poster_isic.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2024/poster_isic.thumbnail.png" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2024/poster_isic.thumbnail.png" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the &lt;strong&gt;9th IEEE Signal Intelligence Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This years motto is "Rifts and Receivers", taking all participants to a rift to a parallel dimension. Fortunately, this rift transmits unconventional messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interdimensional rift has opened up right over the Communications Engineering Lab at KIT. And it seems at the other side of the rift, there is a dimension quite close to ours with a different intitute researching communication engineering. Help us receive, decode and decrypt their signals so we can learn how similar this dimension actually is and maybe we can learn something about their customs and their research.
So help us doing some spontaneous sociology research and @RR#Listen to the rift!#isic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellt euer Team zusammen und helft einem nerdigen Zwerg dabei, sich zu beweisen! Wir haben auch wieder tolle Preise für euch organisiert! Die Infos zum Event werden gesammelt und laufend aktualisiert auf der
In teams of 2-4 motivated students, you will compete to find the hidden messages coming from the rift. As in the last years, there are prizes waiting to be claimed! All info concerning the event is collected and published on our &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/events/sigint-challenge/"&gt;Event-Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are already motivated and can't wait to start? Feel free to check out our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8163122"&gt;Presentation of the ISIC at GECON&lt;/a&gt;. There, you can get some insights into challenges from 2022 and already train your problem-solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there is a complementary Mathworks workshop right before the Kick-off, 30.10.2024, 15:00 at CEL. This workshop will demostrate how to wield the Matlab (and maybe also Simulink) tools to solve an examplary challenge. So if you want to add to your toolbox, please register &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forms.microsoft.com/r/pfQnwVSz2V"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; Kick-off Event: 30.10.2024, 18:00 at CEL (Seminarraum 2.OG, CEL, building 06.45 at Campus West). Wir werden euch sowohl eine kleine Einführung in mögliche Tools geben, als auch die Möglichkeit euch in Teams zusammenzufinden. Kommt also zum Kick-Off auch wenn ihr noch niemand Gleichgesinntes für das Lösen der Signal Intelligence Challenge gefunden habt!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>isic</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2024/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-isic-2024/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science Spotlight: Spaceborne Radar System Technologies</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2024/science-spotlight-airbus/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2024/Science_Spotlight_airbus.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2024/Science_Spotlight_airbus.thumbnail.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2024/Science_Spotlight_airbus.thumbnail.jpg" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time has passed since our last Science Spotlight. Therefore we are delighted to host another event in cooperation with the IHE and Airbus. Alexander Hees and Grzegorz Adamiuk will focus on perspectives for all prospective electrical engineers in spaceborne radar system technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Science Spotlight will take place on the &lt;strong&gt;1st of February 2024&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;NTI lecture hall&lt;/strong&gt; starting at &lt;strong&gt;15:45&lt;/strong&gt;.
We welcome all students, researchers and IEEE members that are interested in the topics. Will provide cold drinks and snacks during and after the event, so you will have the chance to chat with us and the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please register &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://events.vtools.ieee.org/event/register/400929"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to allow for easier planning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>science-spotlight</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2024/science-spotlight-airbus/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:28:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ankündigung: IEEE SB KA ISIC 2023!</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-isic-2022/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/poster_website.webp"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2023/poster_website.thumbnail.webp" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/poster_website.thumbnail.webp" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es freut es uns euch mitteilen zu dürfen, dass wir die mittlerweile &lt;strong&gt;achte IEEE Signal Intelligence Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; ausrichten werden!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir haben diesmal ein nerdiges Motto, und das Motto lautet: &lt;em&gt;"Tunnel-vision"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieses Jahr helfen wir Thraldronlir Orebuckle auf der Suche nach dem mystischen Adamant. Wer ihn auf seiner Suche unterstützt, wird mit hochwertigem Equipment und von Herzen kommenden Preisen belohnt, im besten Fall ist Thraldronlir dann ja reicher Betreiber einer Adamant Miene.
Nachrichten von Thraldronlir können mit dem Affix „@TV#“ und dem Suffix „#isic“ identifiziert werden.
Am 23.11. wird Glorisibelle Metalchin über den Erfolg oder Misserfolg derer entscheiden, die in ihre Fußstapfen treten wollen, also mal sehen ob wir Thraldronlir bis dahin den Vorteil verschaffen können, den er braucht.
Also, @TV#Time to burrow!#isic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellt euer Team zusammen und helft einem nerdigen Zwerg dabei, sich zu beweisen! Wir haben auch wieder tolle Preise für euch organisiert! Die Infos zum Event werden gesammelt und laufend aktualisiert auf der &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/events/sigint-challenge/"&gt;Event-Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ihr seid jetzt schon zu motiviert? Um die Zeit zu überbrücken schaut gerne mal in unsere &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8163122"&gt;Vorstellung der ISIC auf der GECON&lt;/a&gt;, dort könnt ihr einen kleinen Einblick in einige Rätsel von 2022 haben und schauen ob ihr sie anders lösen würdet als wir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; Das Kick-Off-Event findet am 02.11.2023 um 19 Uhr im Seminarraum des Instituts für Nachrichtentechnik (CEL) in Gebäude 06.45 in der Hertzstraße 16, 76187 Karlsruhe (KIT Campus West) statt. Wir werden euch sowohl eine kleine Einführung in mögliche Tools geben, als auch die Möglichkeit euch in Teams zusammenzufinden. Kommt also zum Kick-Off auch wenn ihr noch niemand Gleichgesinntes für das Lösen der Signal Intelligence Challenge gefunden habt!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>isic</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-isic-2022/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 20:37:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Call for Papers: Local Student Paper Contest</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-cfp-spc/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/Plakat_SPC.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2023/Plakat_SPC.thumbnail.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/Plakat_SPC.thumbnail.jpg" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite all KIT students to participate in this year's IEEE local student paper contest by submitting your undergraduate or graduate work by &lt;strong&gt;October 6, 2023&lt;/strong&gt;. The event will not overlap with this year's signal intelligence challenge, but news on that is still pending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last months, we have further planned the prizes you can win, found most of the jury and grew more and more excited to have a look into our students' research. You can hand in your contribution via e-mail to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:info@ieee-ka.de"&gt;info@ieee-ka.de&lt;/a&gt;.
Have a look at the details on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/events/student-paper-contest/"&gt;Event-Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-cfp-spc/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 15:28:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcement: IEEEXtreme 2023</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieeextreme-2023/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We invite all student members to consider participating in the IEEEXtreme Programming Competition at its 17th installment.
IEEEXtreme is a global challenge in which teams of IEEE Student members (advised and proctored by an IEEE member, and often supported by an IEEE Student Branch) compete in a 24-hour time span against each other to solve a set of programming problems.
The Student Branch Karlsruhe will host any Teams from KIT that want to participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total description can be found on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ieeextreme.org/"&gt;IEEEXtreme webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teams consist of up to 3 IEEE Student or Graduate Student members, but can include a maximum of only 2 Graduate Student members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: 25 October 2023, starting at 00:00 UTC and ending at 23:59:59 UTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to participate, please contact us so that venue arrangements can be made and a suitable proctor can be found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>other</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieeextreme-2023/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcement: Hackathon at TU Chemnitz</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-hackathon-chemnitz-2023/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to extend our invitation to all students to participate in the IEEE Hackathon 2023, hosted by TU Chemnitz in collaboration with the IEEE Student Branch TU-Chemnitz. This exciting event is part of the 16th International Workshop on Impedance Spectroscopy (IWIS) and is scheduled to kickstart on the 26th of September 2023.
Students are invited to create and realize their innovative and outstanding ideas in the following areas, but not limited to them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impedance spectroscopy measurements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smart health and rehabilitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telemanipulation and robotic control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green power and smart cities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TUC International Science Hackathon provides an exceptional platform for students like you to showcase your creativity, problem-solving skills, and passion for technology. Whether you're a seasoned developer or just starting your journey in the world of technology, this event is the perfect opportunity for you to join hands with fellow enthusiasts, collaborate, and bring your innovative ideas to life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: September 26th, 2023 to 29th September 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration Deadline&lt;/strong&gt;: August 15th, 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ieeetucsb.com/ieee-hackathon-2023-information/"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ieeetucsb.com/ieee-hackathon-2023/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chat.whatsapp.com/BDQDNfwG3W05mVSktT0V9g"&gt;Whats App Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need further assistance, please don't hesitate to contact the Chemnitz IEEE SB at: &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:ieee.sb.tu.chemnitz@gmail.com"&gt;mailto:ieee.sb.tu.chemnitz@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>other</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-hackathon-chemnitz-2023/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science Spotlight: Medical Engineering &amp; Local Student Paper Contest</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-spotlight-medeng-details/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Andrej</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/Plakat_Science_Spotlight_MedicalEngineering2023.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2023/Plakat_Science_Spotlight_MedicalEngineering2023.thumbnail.png" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/Plakat_Science_Spotlight_MedicalEngineering2023.thumbnail.png" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce our next Science Spotlight titled &lt;cite&gt;Science Spotlight: Medical Engineering&lt;/cite&gt;. This event will be hosted in conjunction with the kickoff for our local student paper contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will host this event on &lt;strong&gt;July 25th&lt;/strong&gt; at the FZI House of Living Labs &lt;strong&gt;Haid-und-Neu-Straße, 76131 Karlsruhe&lt;/strong&gt; starting at &lt;strong&gt;16:00&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a preliminary agenda assembled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kick-Off Local Student Paper Contest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start at 16:00 with a short introduction into the idea and the rules for the student paper contest.
If you are interested in participating in the student paper contest we recommend you attend this presentation and also you
can stay after the event and we will try to answer any open questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FZI Presentations (Oliver Werthwein M.Sc. &amp;amp; Lara Schweickart M.Sc.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the kick-off of the local student paper contest we will have two short presentations about the medical engineering research conducted at FZI.
One presentation will cover the use of AI for analysis and assessment of physical exercises and another presentation will give as an introduction to virtual patient round and contactless recogniction of skin changes in the context of telemedicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FZI House of Living Labs - Tour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an entertaining break in-between presentations we are happy that the FZI will give a tour through their House of Living Labs, showing more of their research in the field of medical engineering. This will include parts of the previously presented topics. We are excited to get a nice insight into the work at FZI House of Living Labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation by CEO of corvolution GmbH (Dr. Silvester Fuhrhop)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our presenter will give as an insight into the work done at the Start-Up corvolution on the topic of developing algorithms and sensor for long-term monitoring of a range of vital signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will provide cold drinks and snacks for all participants and to allow for some cozy Get-Together after the presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please register &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://events.vtools.ieee.org/m/365913"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to allow for easier planning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-spotlight-medeng-details/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 09:43:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Science Spotlight: Medical Engineering &amp; Local Student Paper Contest - Save the Date</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-spotlight-medeng/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Andrej</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some time has passed since our last Science Spotlight. Therefore we are delighted to host another event in cooperation with the Forschungszentrum Informatik (FZI). This time we will focus on the topic of Medical Engineering. We will explore several applications and research conducted at the FZI on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we will kick-off this year's local student paper contest before we start with the presentations. This will include a short introduction to the idea of the local student paper contest and why you should submit your undergraduate or graduate work to the local student paper contest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Science Spotlight will take place on the &lt;strong&gt;25th of July 2023&lt;/strong&gt; at the FZI House of Living Labs &lt;strong&gt;Haid-und-Neu-Straße 5A, 76131 Karlsruhe&lt;/strong&gt; starting at &lt;strong&gt;16:00&lt;/strong&gt;.
We welcome all students, researchers and IEEE members that are interested in the topics. Will provide cold drinks and snacks during and after the event, so you will have the chance to chat with us and the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please register &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://events.vtools.ieee.org/m/365913"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to allow for easier planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will publish a detailed invitiation with the planned presentations and speakers soon!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-spotlight-medeng/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:28:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Announcement: Science Spotlight Machine Learning</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-spotlight-ml/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Charlotte</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/Plakat_Science_Spotlight2023.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2023/Plakat_Science_Spotlight2023.thumbnail.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2023/Plakat_Science_Spotlight2023.thumbnail.jpg" style="width: 250px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce or first Science Spotlight event focusing on varied research on Machine Learning in different areas of engineering.
The Science Spotlight will take place on the &lt;strong&gt;20th of March 2023&lt;/strong&gt; at the Communication Engineering Lab (CEL), &lt;strong&gt;room 213/214 in building 06.45 at the campus west&lt;/strong&gt;, starting at &lt;strong&gt;16:00&lt;/strong&gt;. We welcome all students, researchers and IEEE members that are interested in the topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have planned three presentations and one demostration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Native Wireless: Transforming Wireless Design with Deep Learning (Ass. Prof. Tim O'Shea Ph.D.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, deep learning has revolutionized signal processing in fields like speech, language, and vision. But it's also transforming the world of wireless signal transmission quickly. In this talk, we'll explore how data-driven approaches are used to design machine learning-based radio signal detection, identification, and localization. We'll also discuss how machine learning is being used to create signal transmitters, receivers, and encodings for wireless signals. This exciting area of research has already yielded some impressive prototypes and results and is sure to play a significant role in the future of OpenRAN 5G, 5G Advanced, and 6G wireless systems. Join us to learn more about the software challenges and research trends in this field, and how AI-native communications create disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy Learning for Robotics (Prof. Dr. Gerhard Neumann)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning, robotics and human-robot interaction pose multiple interesting research questions. We will dive into how human non-expert can intuitively teach a robot complex skills as well as allow a robot to learn how to assist and collaborate with humans in an intelligent way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing Neuromorphic Systems (Brian Pachideh M.Sc., &amp;amp; Alexandru Vasilache M.Sc.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our colleaugues at FZI design systems that differ from the classical artificial neural networks and will present us challenges and advantages of designing systems closer corresponding to the biological inspiration that seeding the research into neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For better easier planning, please register &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://events.vtools.ieee.org/m/344624"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; The Science Spotlight is taking place on the 20.03.2023 starting at 16:00 in room 213/214 at the Communication Engineering Lab (CEL) in building 06.45 at Hertzstraße 16, 76187 Karlsruhe (KIT Campus West). There will be snacks, there will be drinks and hopefully lots of interesting discussion. Anyone interested is invited. For better easier planning, please register &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://events.vtools.ieee.org/m/344624"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>spotlight</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2023/ankundigung-ieee-sb-ka-spotlight-ml/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ISIC 2022 - Finale</title><link>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2022/isic22_finale/?utm_source=/announcements/rss.xml&amp;utm_medium=nikola_feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss_feed</link><dc:creator>Andrej</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2022/isic2022_finale.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2022/isic2022_finale.thumbnail.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2022/isic2022_finale.thumbnail.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vergangene Woche ist die 7. IEEE Signal Intelligence Challenge zu Ende gegangen. Nach einem turbulenten Endspurt um die Plätze 2 &amp;amp; 3 hat sich folgende Reihenfolge ergeben: Platz 1 ging wohlverdient an das Team "Die Schlaflosen" mit 2516 Punkten. Mit einem Paukenschlag hat es dieses Team geschafft jede ihnen gestellte Challenge zu lösen! Die Plätze zwei und drei haben sich die Teams "Die Transformierten Fourien" mit 1655 Punkten und "Kein Plan" mit 1545 Punkten aufgeteilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die Siegerehrung fand wie gewohnt im Rahmen des Thanksgiving Events statt. Die Teilnehmer konnten einem höchst spannenden Fachvortrag von Dr. Nico Otterbach von der Firma Rohde &amp;amp; Schwarz zum Thema "Sichere Kommunikation auf SDR-Basis" lauschen. Wir sind sehr froh, dass uns der CEL und KIT Alumnus mit einem Einblick in den spannenden Alltag der sicheren Kommunikationstechnik beehrt hat und hoffen, dass auch die diesjährigen Teilnehmer der ISIC etwas davon mitnehmen konnten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2022/isic2022_vortrag.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="/images/2022/isic2022_vortrag.thumbnail.jpg" class="align-right" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2022/isic2022_vortrag.thumbnail.jpg" style="width: 200px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im Anschluss wurden die Preise an die Sieger vergeben. Platz 1 &amp;amp; 2 erhielten ein SDR, das uns dankenswerterweise von der Firma Analog Devices bereitgestellt wurde, und zwar einen "ADALM-PLUTO", damit können die Teilnehmer nun auch außerhalb der ISIC mit "echten" Signalen experimentieren und ihre Kenntnisse aus dem Studium erweitern. Weiterhin erhielten die Plätze 1 bis 3 noch Raspberry PI PC-400 KITs, die uns von der Firma Rohde &amp;amp; Schwarz bereit gestellt wurden, für allerhand spaßigen Programmier- und Entwicklungsprojekte. Alle teilnehmenden Teams erhielten Gutscheine fürs Vogelbräu, die aus der finanziellen Unterstützung der Firma Procitec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir möchten uns nochmals recht herzlich bei unseren Sponsoren Rohde &amp;amp; Schwarz, Analog Devices und Procitec für die Unterstützung bedanken!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/2022/isic2022_sponsors.png" class="align-left" src="http://www.ieee-ka.de/images/2022/isic2022_sponsors.png" style="width: 400px;"&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finale Punktetabelle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="17%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="3%"&gt;
&lt;col width="4%"&gt;
&lt;col width="4%"&gt;
&lt;col width="4%"&gt;
&lt;col width="4%"&gt;
&lt;col width="4%"&gt;
&lt;col width="8%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead valign="bottom"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class="head"&gt;Team&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;1.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;1.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;2.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;2.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;2.3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;2.4&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;3.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;4.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;4.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;5.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;5.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;6.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;6.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;6.3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;7.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;7.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;8.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;8.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;9.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;10.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;10.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;10.3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;11.1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;11.2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th class="head"&gt;Gesamtpunkte&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Die Schlaflosen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2516&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Die Transformierten
Fourien&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1655&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kein Plan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1545&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Space Girls&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;102&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;818&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DopplerDemons&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;104&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;726&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;BasicBaseBandBitches&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>isic</category><guid>http://www.ieee-ka.de/announcements/2022/isic22_finale/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 22:48:24 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>